Hi, welcome to the lab setup section.
In this section I'm going to tell you how
to download the lab files
that are necessary for completing the
lab exercises. Make sure you have the
VM environment loaded up
from there you open up Firefox and
navigate to the Big Data University
page
and then from there
make sure you go to the Spark Fundamentals
course. Scroll down
to where it says the hands-on lab
exercise.
The instructions to download and
untar the lab files
to the specified location. Again
you are going to visit this page and then click on the download link to get
the lab files onto your hard drive into the
VM
Okay, I have already went ahead and
downloaded this
and it is inside my download folder. Go
to your
download folder and go ahead and extract this
okay
now go ahead
and copy this into the home directory
under virtuser. You are going to paste it into here.
Now that that completed, open up this labfiles folder
make sure all the files in there. you
should have five different folders
There is a lab solutions folder with all the
solutions that you can use
for the lab exercises with NYC taxi
which contains a CSV file for the taxi
data in New York
and there's a subset of the file as well
and there's also one for the weather in
New York City
as well as some data that you can use
for the streams applications
which you will do in one of the lab
exercises and there are some changes.txt
users.txt file and a readme file
as well as a followers.txt
Make sure you have all this set up before you start your lab exercises.
You will need to use all these files.