Hi, Welcome to the lab Getting started
with Spark.
In this lab exercise
you will be able to use the Spark shell
with Scala and Python.
You get to perform basic RDD operations
such as actions and transformations. You
also get to work with caching
in order to speed up any repeated  operations that you might have
Make sure your environment is ready for the lab exercise.
Log into to the virtual machine. Once logged in
you should have a desktop similar to
this. Before we move further,
we should go ahead and set up a Spark
environment variable
that will allow us to quickly start  up the Spark shell. The way you can do that is edit the
bash.rc file and include
the line exports spark_home
This is inside the documentation you
can just copy and paste it into
this file. Don't have to worry about the other stuff just make sure this spark_home
is copied and pasted into here. Save and
quit the file.
Now you can access the Spark shell
using the spark_home environment
variable
So when you first started up the
Quickstart edition, you have to make sure to copy the lab files
onto the image and there was a video
that shows how to do that prior to this
exercise
make sure you do that, if not, go ahead
and get that done before continuing.
Double check that all the files are
inside the virtuser's home directory. The lab files contains folders
and files there you'll be using
throughout the labs
for this course so they are five folders.
Some data from NYC taxi and NYC weather
There is also the lab solutions folder.
Once you have confirmed the files are there, you may close the two windows.
When you start up the
Quickstart edition image initially, Ambari will start up,
and when you log in what start up all the
services for you.
But if that did not happen I'll show you
how you can start the service
manually yourself. Go ahead and open up a web browser.
The login to the Ambari console
is admin the password is also admin.
So I purposely made sure
all the services have stopped in order to demonstrate what you can do to start it up.
Click on the Services menu.
On the left side click on actions and
then start all.
You'll noticed that the services
are now starting. You can click on it to
see the details of each
individual components being started.
On the top
you see the operations. There is one background operation running.
So that I can tell it is still working.
It will take several minutes for all the
services to start up, so I'm
going to speed up the video to the part
where it completes.
Alright so the services have all started. Go ahead and get out at this window
and you can double check that everything has started. In particular you want to make
sure Spark is up.
You may exit out of the Ambari console,   we don't need to use it anymore.
So the next part of the lab exercise,
you will start with working with the
Spark
scala shell. So open up a new terminal
and we're going to copy
the readme file that we have on our
local system
into the HDFS tmp directory.
You can copy and paste the code into
here or type it up.
but essentially you will be copying this
README.md file into the HDFS
/tmp directory.
We're going to be working with the README file
in the first part of this exercise.
I'm showing you here what it would take if we did not set up the spark_home
directory
you have to manually type out the
spark_home directory
in order to access the spark shell. I forgot the bin directory there too.
You can see how this might take some
time. Because we have set up
spark_home, subsequent steps will later
use that spark_home
variable. I went ahead to start up the
spark shell
directory located under the bin
directory. The spark shell is using Scala.
When you start up a shell, a spark context is initialize for you to use
If you do sc, period, and the tab button,
you are going to see a number of functions that are available within the spark context.
Now I'm going to create an RDD file, RDD
from the file README which we have
already uploaded to HDFS
and that is created using the spark context .textFile
As you know
the initial operation is a transformation,
so nothing actually happens. We're just
telling it that we want to create a readme
RDD. Now we just invoke the
readme.count() action which
counts the number line
from that RDD. There's 141 lines.
And by doing the count() and then also the first(),
we have invoked some actions. These actions
were executed against the RDD readme
that we created. So the first line in the
file is the Apache Spark line,
as you can see
Now we can do some transformations,
additional transformations to filter out
lines that contain Spark. So I'm
calling the filter
transformation and then for the
lines that contains the keywords spark
keep it.
So we're filtering everything out to the lines that contains
spark. So Iran that transformation.
Additionally you can actually
chain together transformation and action
on the same line.
So here I did the filter
with this word Spark and I chained it
together with the count
action. You immediately get a return back.
As you can see
there's 21 lines with spark
Sometimes the scala shell will not return back to the prompt. If you see it happen like that,
go ahead and hit the Return key or the Enter key and you will bring it back
to the prompt.