Okay so we finished with the Scala
exercises for now, but keep this terminal
open. We'll continue
with more RDD operations. Open up a new terminal
so that we can do the same steps we've
done using Python this time.
We're going to be working with the same
Readme file
because we have already uploaded that
readme file
to the HDFS we won't need to do it again
but if you skipped through that Scala
section
go ahead and upload that file now. Otherwise
start up, pyspark, which is located under the spark_home
/bin directory. This is now
the Python shell. We can run the Python API
that can invoke the Spark operations.
First thing we're going to do is create the
readme
RDD. Also using the same Spark context
textFile(README.md). Again, that
was just a transformation
so no action has been taken place yet. We do a readme.count(),
this will give us the count of that file. 141
You will noticed that sometimes it doesn't go back to the prompt.
Just hit enter and it will bring you back. I
just went ahead and ran the readme.first()
Again ,same thing. It just grabs the
first-line from the readme RDD.
Next we're going to
filter, user the filter transformation
to find the lines with the word spark in
it.
That creates the linesWithSpark RDD
likewise, you can also chain together
multiple operations. So I did a filter
and then I chained together the count operation to get it to return
the value 21, which is the number of lines
containing the words spark in it.
okay so that's pretty much the same task
we've done for the Python shell. Go ahead and
minimize the Python shell. We will resume with Scala
and focus more on some additional RDD
operations.
In particular we're going to look at the
map and the reduce
operations. This case here we're going to
take the readme file and have it split the
line
on the space, in order to find the size
of that line.Essentially we're doing the
map operation to get it to split
and then the size. The second part is to
reduce
the map output
to find the line with the most words in
it. Essentially we want to see
which lines has the most words and that's
what the reduce operation here is doing
So line 15 contains the most word
in it. Again I have to hit the enter key
to get back to the Scala prompt. In this next step,
I want to show you how you can import
additional libraries
to do what you need to do. In this case
we're going to do the same operation we
just done,
but this time using the math.max()
function so I imported the
math library from Java and then
this line now, the map is still the same
were gonna split on the space and going to find the size of the line and then we are going to
reduce
the output using this
math.max operation and this will
show you that
the result will still be the same. We
just used a different route of
accessing it and in this case we're using
a library to help us accomplish the task.
Spark also supports MapReduce
like as a data flow pattern, so not just
the
the map and reduce you just saw, but the map and reduce data flow which will
used to do a word count. Now this is
something you've all been familiar with.
So in MapReduce you actually have
to code quite a few statements in order to
get the word count
of a file. In Spark it is actually a simple
chain of operations. First thing you have do is split the line up
individually by the words and then you will map
the word to the value of one.
So essentially know every word and get
value one and then finally you reduced
by that key
which is the word and you add in all the
values together
to get you the number of occurrences of a
particular word.
That was just the transformation.
Let's invoke an action on it. We're going to call the collect() action.
to take a look at all the work count.
Now as you can see here, everything is now output on a terminal,
and you can see that the words and the
number of occurrences within the readme file. Now you can do the same thing
with Python, so I am going to jump back to the Python shell and show you again how to
do the normal map and reduce to
find the line with the most words in
it. So, in Python
we're calling the map function to split lines up and then grab the length of the
number words for that line and
then we reduce it
to see which one has the greater number
of words.
That's what will be finally printed to the output, and that is 15.
So this same results because we're
working with the same file.
Likewise
you can also use a math function of some
sort. In this case
we're gonna define the max function. So the max of a and b
So if a is greater than b, we're going to return a
otherwise we're going to return b.
Basically the same operations
there were performed in the
math.max() function. Okay so now
you have defined that max function,
we're going to use it
in the map and reduce to
find the number of lines with the most words in it.
The mapping parts stays the same.  We're still splitting up and then counting the number of
words
and then we invoke the reduce by passing in the max function and in this case
again
it is the same number which is expected.
To do a word count,
we're going do the flatMap first. flatMap,
what it does is it essentially breaks up the individual
lines into words and then
from the individual words we do a map
operation to get it to a value
1 and it finally we can add up all those
values to get the number of occurrences
and we run the collect() action again to see the results.