Now we're going to look at Spark's shared variables.
There's two types that we're going to
talk about today. We have the broadcast
variable
and accumulators. Broadcast variables are useful for
when you have a large dataset you want
to use across the worker nodes.
Instead of having to send out the entire
dataset, you just send out the variable.
So here I am going to create a simple
broadcast variable with an array three
integers
and then to get a value, you simply call
the value
function. Again
useful for using with large datasets so
you don't have to send out across the entire
cluster.
Accumulators are another type of variables
that can be added through an associative
operation.
It is used to implement counters and
sums, efficiently in parallel.
Spark natively supports numeric types
accumulators and standard mutable
collections.
Programmers can extend these types for
new types. Only the driver can read the
values
of the accumulators. The worker nodes can only invoke
or increment the value. So here I create
a simple accumulator
with the value of 0.
So it starts up at zero and now we are going to test this out
by creating an array of four integers:
one two three and four and then we're going to iterate through the array.
So for each element of the array, add the
the value to the accumulator, so
essentially we're going to sum up the
values of the array into the accumulator.
variable. Go ahead and run this
to create and
increment the accumulator.
So once that is done, the accumulator values has been
incremented already. To see the value
you also
call the value() operator and you'll see 10
the sum of all the array elements total up to 10. Again
this command to get the value of the
accumulator can only be invoked on the driver side
The worker nodes can only increment or add
to the accumulator. They cannot see the
value on the accumulator.
Finally, we are going take a quick look at
the
key-value pair. We've seen this
already with the
joined RDD.  You can create a key/value pair by
just putting it in the parentheses like
I'm doing here and then to access it the
individual elements it starts with the
._ notation. Index 1 is at the one and index 2 is at
the 2, so it starts at the one index.