Welcome to Exercise 2 - Resilient
Distributed Datasets.
In this exercise you going to be able
to create
a RDD from an external data set. You are going to be able to view a direct
acyclic graph of an RDD, something
transformations
update when they are executed and you'll be able to work with various RDD operations
including some that you have seen
already in lab one but also
new operations you haven't seen yet and
also you'll get to work with shared
variables
and key value pairs. So in this lab we're
going to
be working with some log files. We will have to upload these log files
into HDFS and we're going to be working with the Spark
log files. It actually doesn't matter which
log files you choose
The point here is just to show how
you can analyze something such as a
log file.
using Spark. So go ahead and copy and paste
the command in to copy a log file
into HDFS.
Here I get a listing of the log files
available and I'm just going to choose one.
It doesn't matter which one you pick and
most likely the ones on your system
will be different from the ones I'm
going to use, but that's not
the important point here. So just pick
whichever one you want we're going to copy
into the /tmp directory
and we can we going to rename it to the sparkLog.out filename
That will make it a lot easier to work with
the later. Ok, if you want, you can view it
quickly on the HDFS using the
hadoop fs -ls
command to make sure that it
is inside the /tmp directory
sparkLog.out has been copied over. You
should already have the readme file
copied as well.
from the first lab exercise. If not, copy
that one in and then you also need to
copy the
changes.txt file. This file is actually
part of the lab files that you
you downloaded, so it is under the
/home/virtuser/labfiles directory.
I'm going to copy that changes.txt
into the /tmp directory as well.
So now we have all the files that we are
going to be using
for this lab exercise. I did another
listing
to take a look to make sure I've copied everything in correctly.
So now we're going to do some operations in Scala. I'm going to launch
the Scala shell. We are going to analyze
the log files that we just uploaded.
First thing to do
is to create the RDD. You are going to create the RDD using a log file
and in the terminal you have a Spark Context already initialized
for you. We are going to call this
log file and it is going to point to the sparkLog.out.
You've seen the filter operation before
so let's see it again just to make sure.
We are going to filter out all the lines that contain 'info'
We're interested in some
information
pertaining to Spark for that particular log file and we are going to filter this out into the
info RDD.
Let's do a quick count of this info and
see how many lines contain the
info keyword. In this case they are eight.
You know you can
chain together RDD operations. You have seen this already as well.
We are going to look for the lines that contains Spark
and just do a count on it right away. We don't need to create an RDD for it.
Chain everything together, executed it to get the value.
Your values will most likely be different obviously because you are using
a different log file.
You have also seen the collect
operation before as well. This collect operation prints out the arrays..
So now I want to see, in particular, which lines
contains Spark from the log file, so I call
the collect action.
So all this time we've been talking a
lot about the DAG, the direct
acyclic graph. This is the graph that gets
updated
when we invoke transformation on it so
this provides fault tolerance. If a node becomes unavailable for some reason
and a it is brought backup it just needs to
borrow the DAG from its neighboring node
and it will use that to get back into
its original state. To find the DAG,
just invoke the toDebugString() operation.This will tell you
the path that it took to get to where it is
now. It started off as a
Hadoop RDD and then we did some map and filter on it, depending on
operations that we called.