Welcome to exercise 3: Creating a Spark Application
This exercise will show you how to
create a Spark
application, link and compile it with the
respective program languages and
run the applications on the Spark cluster. The goal of this lab exercise is to show you how
to create and run a Spark program.
That is not to focus on how to program
in Scala or Python,
or even Java. The business logic up the
application can be anything you need for
your particular application.
Before you get started, you are going to have to set up the VM
with the appropriate build tools. You can,
of course, use any build tools you prefer.
This is just the one that I've selected
to use. I went ahead and downloaded
the Scala SBT in order to package
Scala applications.
and then I downloaded and I extracted
the
package under the
/usr/local directory. I also created some
environmental variables
to make sure I can use and run SBT
anywhere within the machine. I'm going to show you what it looks like in my
.bashrc
This is what I created when I downloaded
SBT package.
I put it under the /usr/local directory.
I have that all set up. You have to update
and
change the path accordingly to what
package name or
the package build tools that you download. Back to the terminal
you start by creating a Spark application in Scala.
The examples are actually available on the image
under the examples subfolder of spark or
you can find it on Spark's website.
First thing is create a SparkPi
directory
under your /home/virtuser/. Then
under this SparkPi directory you had to
set up by a typical directory structure
for the application using the SBT build tool.
So need to make the folders
source, main, and scala. You can do this
separately on individual lines or you
can do it on the same line
with the command option  -p
So that created the three directory structures.
Go ahead and change into the
scala directory --
now just making sure everything's there.
Go ahead and change into the scala
directory. This is where you will create and
save your SparkPi.scala class.
You can use any form of text editor you wish. I'm going to straight on the
command
terminal. Copy and paste
the entire content for the code from the
lab exercise
doc into the terminal. We're going to go
each of these lines individually but
just go ahead and quit out of that cat by
going CTRL+D and that will save the file.
Let's explain a little bit about each of the lines. Go ahead and print out this file,
SparkPi.scala. First two lines
are just import statements
necessary to run a Spark application.
We also have a math library in there because we're going to do some math functions to
compute pie.
Of course, you are going to need the Spark package. Then everything else
is setting it up. You are going to have to create a Spark configuration object.
I gave it an an application name
of SparkPi. You will pass that
Spark configuration object to the Spark Context
so you have to create the Spark Context.
Th next few lines of codes are the business logic required to calculate pi
and finally you print now the
calculation of Pi
onto the console and you have to be sure
to stop the spark context
As opposed to
using a terminal, an application you need
define the Spark Context and also
stop it.
The terminal you can get this Spark Context automatically and
they will end when you close that shell. At this point,
you have to create some dependencies
for spark so
go to the root of the SparkPi
directory and create a file called
sparkpi.sbt. Inside this sparkpi file,
copy and paste the lines for the dependencies into it.
If you are using a different library,
then change to version accordingly. So now your directory should look like this.
sparkpi.sbt on top, on the root directory
and then to package just call command
sbt package
This is gonna run through and
package up this simple
SparkPi application. Initially when you run
this is gonna take a while
because it has to download all the
necessary dependencies. I'm not gonna make
you sit through
this entire process unless you actually
doing it yourself but
for the purpose of this video I'm going
to speed up and
bring it to the end.
So it finished packaging the file.
In order to run the application, you are going to use the spark-submit script,
which is located under $SPARK_HOME/bin
We're going to pass in some parameters as well.
We went ahead and ran it.
Don't worry, I'm going to go back up and explain
some of the parameters that we used.
So the application completed running,
and going all the way back up.
Obviously this is a script right here. spark_submit. and then the class name is SparkPi
and then you tell it which
is the master node. In our case is going
to be the local node running with 4
cores. You need a minimum of two cores for parallelism. Then you provide the path to the
jar file. You'll notice some errors here.
Don't worry about, it's not critical
to the application. The application ran and successfully completed.
and now we need to look through this output here
to see what output came out. Here it
shows that Pi is roughly 3.13.
and obviously every time you run it
would be slightly different based on the
mathematical
computations, but again the purpose was
to show you how you can create
and run Spark applications
using Scala.