You heard me mention direct acyclic graph
several times now. On this slide, you will
see how to view the DAG of any particular
RDD. A DAG is essentially a graph of the business
logic and does not get executed until an action
is called -- often called lazy evaluation.
To view the DAG of a RDD after a series of
transformation, use the toDebugString method
as you see here on the slide. It will display
the series of transformation that Spark will
go through once an action is called. You read
it from the bottom up. In the sample DAG shown
on the slide, you can see that it starts as
a textFile and goes through a series of transformation
such as map and filter, followed by more map
operations. Remember, that it is this behavior
that allows for fault tolerance. If a node
goes offline and comes back on, all it has
to do is just grab a copy of this from a neighboring
node and rebuild the graph back to where it
was before it went offline.
In the next several slides, you will see at
a high level what happens when an action is
executed.
Let's look at the code first. The goal here
is to analyze some log files. The first line
you load the log from the hadoop file system.
The next two lines you filter out the messages
within the log errors. Before you invoke some
action on it, you tell it to cache the filtered
dataset - it doesn't actually cache it yet
as nothing has been done up until this point.
Then you do more filters to get specific error
messages relating to mysql and php followed
by the count action to find out how many errors
were related to each of those filters.
Now let's walk through each of the steps.
The first thing that happens when you load
in the text file is the data is partitioned
into different blocks across the cluster.
Then the driver sends the code to be executed
on each block. In the example, it would be
the various transformations and actions that
will be sent out to the workers. Actually,
it is the executor on each workers that is
going to be performing the work on each block.
You will see a bit more on executors in a
later lesson.
Then the executors read the HDFS blocks to
prepare the data for the operations in parallel.
After a series of transformations, you want
to cache the results up until that point into
memory. A cache is created.
After the first action completes, the results
are sent back to the driver. In this case,
we're looking for messages that relate to
mysql. This is then returned back to the driver.
To process the second action, Spark will use
the data on the cache -- it doesn't need to
go to the HDFS data again. It just reads it
from the cache and processes the data from
there.
Finally the results go back to the driver
and we have completed a full cycle.
So a quick recap. This is a subset of some
of the transformations available. The full
list of them can be found on Spark's website.
Remember that Transformations are essentially
lazy evaluations. Nothing is executed until
an action is called. Each transformation function
basically updates the graph and when an action
is called, the graph is executed. Transformation
returns a pointer to the new RDD.
I'm not going to read through this as you
can do so yourself. I'll just point out some
things I think are important.
The flatMap function is similar to map, but
each input can be mapped to 0 or more output
items. What this means is that the returned
pointer of the func method, should return
a sequence of objects, rather than a single
item. It would mean that the flatMap would
flatten a list of lists for the operations
that follows. Basically this would be used
for MapReduce operations where you might have
a text file and each time a line is read in,
you split that line up by spaces to get individual
keywords. Each of those lines ultimately is
flatten so that you can perform the map operation
on it to map each keyword to the value of
one.
The join function combines two sets of key
value pairs and return a set of keys to a
pair of values from the two initial set. For
example, you have a K,V pair and a K,W pair.
When you join them together, you will get
a K, (V,W) set.
The reduceByKey function aggregates on each
key by using the given reduce function. This
is something you would use in a WordCount
to sum up the values for each word to count
its occurrences.
Action returns values. Again, you can find
more information on Spark's website. This
is just a subset.
The collect function returns all the elements
of the dataset as an array of the driver program.
This is usually useful after a filter or another
operation that returns a significantly small
subset of data to make sure your filter function
works correctly.
The count function returns the number of elements
in a dataset and can also be used to check
and test transformations.
The take(n) function returns an array with
the first n elements. Note that this is currently
not executed in parallel. The driver computes
all the elements.
The foreach(func) function run a function
func on each element of the dataset.