Spark runs on Windows or Unix-like systems.
The lab exercises that are part of this course
will be running with IBM BigInsights. The
information on this slide shows you how you
can install the standalone version yourself
with all the default values that come along
with it.
To install Spark, simply download the pre-built
version of Spark and place a compiled version
of Spark on each node of your cluster. Then
you can manually start the cluster by executing
./sbin/start-master.sh . In the lab, the start
script is different, and you will see this
in the lab exercise guide.
Again, the default URL to the master UI is
on port 8080. The lab exercise environment
will be different and you will see this in
the guide as well.
You can check out Spark's website for more
information:
Spark jobs can be written in Scala, Python
or Java. Spark shells are available for Scala
or Python. This course will not teach how
to program in each specific language, but
will cover how to use them within the context
of Spark. It is recommended that you have
at least some programming background to understand
how to code in any of these.
If you are setting up the Spark cluster yourself,
you will have to make sure that you have a
compatible version of the programming language
you choose to use. This information can be
found on Spark's website. In the lab environment,
everything has been set up for you - all you
do is launch up the shell and you are ready
to go.
Spark itself is written in the Scala language,
so it is natural to use Scala to write Spark
applications. This course will cover code
examples from by Scala, Python, and Java.
Java 8 actually supports the functional programming
style to include lambdas, which concisely
captures the functionality that are executed
by the Spark engine. This bridges the gap
between Java and Scala for developing applications
on Spark. Java 6 and 7 is supported, but would
require more work and an additional library
to get the same amount of functionality as
you would using Scala or Python.
Here we have a brief overview of Scala. Everything
in Scala is an object. The primitive types
that is defined by Java such as int or boolean
are objects in Scala. Functions are objects
in Scala and will play an important role in
how applications are written for Spark.
Numbers are objects. This means that in an
expression that you see here: 1 + 2 * 3 / 4
actually means that the individual numbers
invoke the various identifiers +,-,*,/ with
the other numbers passed in as arguments using
the dot notation.
Functions are objects. You can pass functions
as arguments into another function. You can
store them as variables. You can return them
from other functions. The function declaration
is the function name followed by the list
of parameters and then the return type.
This slide and the next is just to serve as
a very brief overview of Scala. If you wish
to learn more about Scala, check out its website
for tutorials and guide. Throughout this course,
you will see examples in Scala that will have
explanations on what it does. Remember, the
focus of this course is on the context of
Spark. It is not intended to teach Scala,
Python or Java.
Anonymous functions are very common in Spark
applications. Essentially, if the function
you need is only going to be required once,
there is really no value in naming it. Just
use it anonymously on the go and forget about
it. For example, suppose you have a timeFlies
function and it in, you just print a statement
to the console. In another function, oncePerSecond,
you need to call this timeFlies function.
Without anonymous functions, you would code
it like the top example be defining the timeFlies
function. Using the anonymous function capability,
you just provide the function with arguments,
the right arrow, and the body of the function
after the right arrow as in the bottom example.
Because this is the only place you will be
using this function, you do not need to name
the function.
The Spark shell provides a simple way to learn
Spark's API. It is also a powerful tool to
analyze data interactively. The Shell is available
in either Scala, which runs on the Java VM,
or Python. To start up Scala, execute the
command spark-shell from within the Spark's
bin directory. To create a RDD from a text
file, invoke the textFile method with the
sc object, which is the SparkContext. We'll
talk more about these functions in a later
lesson.
To start up the shell for Python, you would
execute the pyspark command from the same
bin directory. Then, invoking the textFile
command will also create a RDD for that text
file.
In the lab exercise, you will start up either
of the shells and run a series of RDD transformations
and actions to get a feel of how to work with
Spark. In a later lesson and exercise, you
will get to dive deeper into RDDs.
Having completed this lesson, you should now
understand what Spark is all about and why
you would want to use it. You should be able
to list and describe the components in the
Spark stack as well as understand the basics
of Spark's primary abstraction, the RDDs.
You also saw how to download and install Spark's
standalone if you wish to, or you can use
the provided lab environment. You got a brief
overview of Scala and saw how to launch and
use the two Spark Shells.
You have completed this lesson. Go on to the
first lab exercise and then proceed to the
next lesson in this course.