Here is a really short overview of the machine
learning library. The MLlib library contains
algorithms and utilities for classification,
regression, clustering, collaborative filtering
and dimensionality reduction. Essentially,
you would use this for specific machine learning
use cases that requires these algorithms.
In the lab exercise, you will use the clustering
K-Means algorithm on a set of taxi drop off
points to figure out potentially where the
best place to hail a cab would be.
The GraphX is another library that sits on
top of the Spark Core. It is basically a graph
processing library which can used for social
networks and language modeling. Graph data
and the requirement for graph parallel systems
is becoming more common, which is why the
GraphX library was developed. Specific scenarios
would not be efficient if it is processed
using the data-parallel model. A need for
the graph-parallel model is introduced with
new graph-parallel systems like Giraph and
GraphLab to efficiently execute graph algorithms
much faster than general data-parallel systems.
There are new inherent challenges that comes
with graph computations, such as constructing
the graph, modifying its structure, or expressing
computations that span several graphs. As
such, it is often necessary to move between
table and graph views depending on the objective
of the application and the business requirements.
The goal of GraphX is to optimize the process
by making it easier to view data both as a
graph and as collections, such as RDD, without
data movement or duplication.
The lab exercise goes through an example of
loading in a text file and creating a graph
from it to find attributes of the top users.
Having completed this lesson, you should be
able to understand and use the various Spark
libraries.
Complete lab exercise #4, creating applications
using Spark SQL, MLib, Spark Streaming, and
GraphX and then proceed to the next lesson
in this course.