Here we have a picture of the Spark unified
stack. As you can see, the Spark core is at
the center of it all. The Spark core is a
general-purpose system providing scheduling,
distributing, and monitoring of the applications
across a cluster. Then you have the components
on top of the core that are designed to interoperate
closely, letting the users combine them, just
like they would any libraries in a software
project. The benefit of such a stack is that
all the higher layer components will inherit
the improvements made at the lower layers.
Example: Optimization to the Spark Core will
speed up the SQL, the streaming, the machine
learning and the graph processing libraries
as well. The Spark core is designed to scale
up from one to thousands of nodes. It can
run over a variety of cluster managers including
Hadoop YARN and Apache Mesos. Or simply, it
can even run as a standalone with its own
built-in scheduler.
Spark SQL is designed to work with the Spark
via SQL and HiveQL (a Hive variant of SQL).
Spark SQL allows developers to intermix SQL
with Spark's programming language supported
by Python, Scala, and Java.
Spark Streaming provides processing of live
streams of data. The Spark Streaming API closely
matches that of the Sparks Core's API, making
it easy for developers to move between applications
that processes data stored in memory vs arriving
in real-time. It also provides the same degree
of fault tolerance, throughput, and scalability
that the Spark Core provides.
Machine learning, MLlib is the machine learning
library that provides multiple types of machine
learning algorithms. All of these algorithms
are designed to scale out across the cluster
as well.
GraphX is a graph processing library with
APIs to manipulate graphs and performing graph-parallel
computations.
Here's a brief history of Spark. I'm not
going to spend too much time on this as you
can easily find more information for yourself
if you are interested. Basically, you can
see that MapReduce started out over a decade
ago. MapReduce was designed as a fault tolerant
framework that ran on commodity systems. Spark
comes out about a decade later with the similar
framework to run data processing on commodity
systems also using a fault tolerant framework.
MapReduce started off as a general batch processing
system, but there are two major limitations.
1) Difficulty in programming directly in MR
and 2) Batch jobs do not fit many use cases.
So this spawned specialized systems to handle
other use cases. When you try to combine these
third party systems in your applications,
there are a lot of overhead.
Taking a looking at the code size of some
applications on the graph on this slide, you
can see that Spark requires a considerable
amount less. Even with Spark's libraries,
it only adds a small amount of code due to
how tightly everything is integrated with
very little overhead. There is great value
to be able to express a wide variety of use
cases with few lines of code.
Now let's get into the core of Spark. Spark's
primary core abstraction is called Resilient
Distributed Dataset or RDD. Essentially it
is just a distributed collection of elements
that is parallelized across the cluster. You
can have two types of RDD operations. Transformations
and Actions. Transformations are those that
do not return a value. In fact, nothing is
evaluated during the definition of these transformation
statements. Spark just creates these Direct
Acyclic Graphs or DAG, which will only be
evaluated at runtime. We call this lazy evaluation.
The fault tolerance aspect of RDDs allows
Spark to reconstruct the transformations used
to build the lineage to get back the lost
data.
Actions are when the transformations get evaluted
along with the action that is called for that
RDD. Actions return values. For example, you
can do a count on a RDD, to get the number
of elements within and that value is returned.
So you have an image of a base RDD shown here
on the slide. The first step is loading the
dataset from Hadoop. Then uou apply successive
transformations on it such as filter, map,
or reduce. Nothing actually happens until
an action is called. The DAG is just updated
each time until an action is called. This
provides fault tolerance. For example, let's
say a node goes offline. All it needs to do
when it comes back online is to re-evaluate
the graph to where it left off.
Caching is provided with Spark to enable the
processing to happen in memory. If it does
not fit in memory, it will spill to disk.