Hi - Welcome to Spark Fundamentals. Introduction
to Spark.
Objectives:
After completing this lesson, you should be
able to explain the purpose of Spark and understand
why and when you would use Spark. You should
be able to list and describe the components
of the Spark unified stack. You will be able
to understand the basics of the Resilient Distributed
Dataset, Spark's primary data abstraction.
Then you will see how to download and install
Spark standalone to test it out yourself.
You will get an overview of Scala and Python
to prepare for using the two Spark shells.
There is an explosion of data. No matter where
you look, data is everywhere. You get data
from social media such as Twitter feeds, Facebook
posts, SMS, and a variety of others. The need
to be able to process those data as quickly
as possible becomes more important than ever.
How can you find out what your customers want
and be able to offer it to them right away?
You do not want to wait hours for a batch
job to complete. You need to have it in minutes
or less.
MapReduce has been useful, but the amount
of time it takes for the jobs to run is no
longer acceptable in most situations. The
learning curve to writing a MapReduce job
is also difficult as it takes specific programming
knowledge and the know-how. Also, MapReduce
jobs only work for a specific set of use cases.
You need something that works for a wider
set of use cases.
Apache Spark was designed as a computing platform
to be fast, general-purpose, and easy to use.
It extends the MapReduce model and takes it
to a whole other level.
The speed comes from the in-memory computations.
Applications running in memory allows for
a much faster processing and response. Spark
is even faster than MapReduce for complex
applications on disks.
This generality covers a wide range of workloads
under one system. You can run batch application
such as MapReduce types jobs or iterative
algorithms that builds upon each other. You
can also run interactive queries and process
streaming data with your application. In a
later slide, you'll see that there are a
number of libraries which you can easily use
to expand beyond the basic Spark capabilities.
The ease of use with Spark enables you to
quickly pick it up using simple APIs for Scala,
Python and Java. As mentioned, there are additional
libraries which you can use for SQL, machine
learning, streaming, and graph processing.
Spark runs on Hadoop clusters such as Hadoop
YARN or Apache Mesos, or even as a standalone
with its own scheduler.
You may be asking, why would I want to use
Spark and what would I use it for? As you
know, Spark is related to MapReduce in a sense
that it expands on its capabilities.
Like MapReduce, Spark provides parallel distributed
processing, fault tolerance on commodity hardware,
scalability, etc. Spark adds to the concept
with aggressively cached in-memory distributed
computing, low latency, high level APIs and
stack of high level tools described on the
next slide. This saves time and money.
There are two groups that we can consider
here who would want to use Spark: Data Scientists
and Engineers. You may ask, but aren't they
similar? In a sense, yes, they do have overlapping
skill sets, but for our purpose, we'll define
data scientist as those who need to analyze
and model the data to obtain insight. They
would have techniques to transform the data
into something they can use for data analysis.
They will use Spark for its ad-hoc analysis
to run interactive queries that will give
them results immediately. Data scientists
may also have experience using SQL, statistics,
machine learning and some programming, usually
in Python, MatLab or R. Once the data scientists
have obtained insights on the data and later
someone determines that there's a need develop
a production data processing application,
a web application, or some system to act upon
the insight, the person called upon to work
on it would be the engineers.
Engineers would use Spark's programming
API to develop a system that implement business
use cases. Spark parallelize these applications
across the clusters while hiding the complexities
of distributed systems programming and fault
tolerance. Engineers can use Spark to monitor,
inspect and tune applications.
For everyone else, Spark is easy to use with
a wide range of functionality. The product
is mature and reliable.