There are three ways to monitor Spark applications.
The first way is the Web UI. The default port
is 4040. The port in the lab environment is
8088. The information on this UI is available
for the duration of the application. If you
want to see the information after the fact,
set the spark.eventLog.enabled to true before
starting the application. The information
will then be persisted to storage as well.
Metrics is another way to monitor Spark applications.
The metric system is based on the Coda Hale
Metrics Library. You can customize it so that
it reports to a variety of sinks such as CSV.
You can configure the metrics system in the
metrics.properties file under the conf directory.
Finally, you can also use external instrumentations
to monitor Spark. Gangalia is used to view
overall cluster utilization and resource bottlenecks.
Various OS profiling tools and JVM utilities
can also be used for monitoring Spark.
The Web UI is found on port 4040, by default,
and shows the information for the current
application while it is running.
The Web UI contains the following information.
A list of scheduler stages and tasks.
A summary of RDD sizes and memory usage.
Environmental information and information
about the running executors.
To view the history of an application after
it has ran, you can start up the history server.
The history server can be configured on the
amount of memory allocated for it, the various
JVM options, the public address for the server,
and a number of properties.
You will see all of this in the lab exercise.
Spark programs can be bottlenecked by any
resource in the cluster. Due to Spark's nature
of the in-memory computations, data serialization
and memory tuning are two areas that will
improve performance. Data serialization is
crucial for network performance and to reduce
memory use. It is often the first thing you
should look at when tuning Spark applications.
Spark provides two serialization libraries.
Java serialization provides a lot more flexibility,
but it is quiet slow and leads to large serialized
objects. This is the default library that
Spark uses to serialize objects. Kyro serialization
is much quicker than Java, but does not support
all Serializable types. It would require you
to register these types in advance for best
performance. To use Kyro serialization, you
can set it using the SparkConf object.
With memory tuning, you have to consider three
things. The amount of memory used by the objects
(whether or not you want the entire object
to fit in memory). The cost of accessing those
objects and the overhead garbage collection.
You can determine how much memory your dataset
requires by creating a RDD, put it into cache,
and look at the SparkContext log on your driver
program. Examining that log will show you
how much memory your dataset uses.
Few tips to reduce the amount of memory used
by each object. Try to avoid Java features
that add overhead such as pointer based data
structures and wrapper objects. If possible
go with arrays or primitive types and try
to avoid nested structures.
Serialized storage can also help to reduce
memory usage. The downside would be that it
will take longer to access the object because
you have to deserialized it before you can
use it.
You can collect statistics on the garbage
collection to see how frequently it occurs
and the amount of time spent on it. To do
so, add the line to the SPARK_JAVA_OPTS environment
variable.
The level of parallelism should be considered
in order to fully utilize your cluster. It
is automatically set to the file size of the
task, but you can configure this through optional
parameters such as in the SparkContext.textFile.
You can also set the default level in the
spark.default.parallelism config property.
Generally, it is recommended to set 2-3 tasks
per CPU core in the cluster.
Sometimes when your RDD does not fit in memory,
you will get an OutOfMemoryError. In cases
like this, often by increasing the level of
parallelism will resolve this issue. By increasing
the level, each set of task input will be
smaller, so it can fit in memory.
Using Spark's capability to broadcast large
variables greatly reduces the size of the
serialized object. A good example would be
if you have some type of static lookup table.
Consider turning that into a broadcast variable
so it does not need to be passed on to each
of the worker nodes.
Spark prints the serialized size of each tasks
in the master. Check that out to examine if
any tasks are too large. If you see some tasks
larger than 20KB, it's worth taking a look
to see if you can optimize it further, such
as creating broadcast variables.
Having completed this lesson, you should be
able to describe the cluster overview. You
should also know where and how to set Spark
configuration properties. You also saw how
to monitor Spark using the UI, metrics or
various external tools. Finally, you should
understand some performance tuning considerations.
Next steps. Complete lab exercise #5 and then,
congratulations, you have completed this course.