Hi. Welcome to the Spark Fundamentals course.
This lesson will cover Resilient Distributed
Dataset.
After completing this lesson, you should be
able to understand and describe Spark's primary
data abstraction, the RDD. You should know
how to create parallelized collections from
internal and external datasets. You should
be able to use RDD opeartions such as Transformations
and Actions. Finally, I will also show you
how to take advantage of Spark's shared variables
and key-value pairs.
Resilient Distributed Dataset (RDD) is Spark's
primary abstraction. RDD is a fault tolerant
collection of elements that can be parallelized.
In other words, they can be made to be operated
on in parallel. They are also immutable. These
are the fundamental primary units of data
in Spark.
When RDDs are created, a direct acyclic graph
(DAG) is created. This type of operation is
called transformations. Transformations makes
updates to that graph, but nothing actually
happens until some action is called. Actions
are another type of operations. We'll talk
more about this shortly. The notion here is
that the graphs can be replayed on nodes that
need to get back to the state it was before
it went offline - thus providing fault tolerance.
The elements of the RDD can be operated on
in parallel across the cluster. Remember,
transformations return a pointer to the RDD
created and actions return values that comes
from the action.
There are three methods for creating a RDD.
You can parallelize an existing collection.
This means that the data already resides within
Spark and can now be operated on in parallel.
As an example, if you have an array of data,
you can create a RDD out of it by calling
the parallelized method. This method returns
a pointer to the RDD. So this new distributed
dataset can now be operated upon in parallel
throughout the cluster.
The second method to create a RDD, is to reference
a dataset. This dataset can come from any
storage source supported by Hadoop such as
HDFS, Cassandra, HBase, Amazon S3, etc.
The third method to create a RDD is from transforming
an existing RDD to create a new RDD. In other
words, let's say you have the array of data
that you parallelized earlier. Now you want
to filter out strings that are shorter than
20 characters. A new RDD is created using
the filter method.
A final point on this slide. Spark supports
text files, SequenceFiles and any other Hadoop
InputFormat.
Here is a quick example of how to create an
RDD from an existing collection of data. In
the examples throughout the course, unless
otherwise indicated, we're going to be using
Scala to show how Spark works. In the lab
exercises, you will get to work with Python
and Java as well. So the first thing is to
launch the Spark shell. This command is located
under the $SPARK_HOME/bin directory. In the
lab environment, SPARK_HOME is the path to
where Spark was installed.
Once the shell is up, create some data with
values from 1 to 10,000. Then, create an RDD
from that data using the parallelize method
from the SparkContext, shown as sc on the
slide. This means that the data can now be
operated on in parallel.
We will cover more on the SparkContext, the
sc object that is invoking the parallelized
function, in our programming lesson, so for
now, just know that when you initialize a
shell, the SparkContext, sc, is initialized
for you to use.
The parallelize method returns a pointer to
the RDD. Remember, transformations operations
such as parallelize, only returns a pointer
to the RDD. It actually won't create that
RDD until some action is invoked on it. With
this new RDD, you can perform additional transformations
or actions on it such as the filter transformation.
Another way to create a RDD is from an external
dataset. In the example here, we are creating
a RDD from a text file using the textFile
method of the SparkContext object. You will
see plenty more examples of how to create
RDD throughout this course.
Here we go over some basic operations. You
have seen how to load a file from an external
dataset. This time, however, we are loading
a file from the hdfs. Loading the file creates
a RDD, which is only a pointer to the file.
The dataset is not loaded into memory yet.
Nothing will happen until some action is called.
The transformation basically updates the direct
acyclic graph (DAG).
So the transformation here is saying map each
line s, to the length of that line. Then,
the action operation is reducing it to get
the total length of all the lines. When the
action is called, Spark goes through the DAG
and applies all the transformation up until
that point, followed by the action and then
a value is returned back to the caller.
A common example is a MapReduce word count.
You first split up the file by words and then
map each word into a key value pair with the
word as the key, and the value of 1. Then
you reduce by the key, which adds up all the
value of the same key, effectively, counting
the number of occurrences of that key. Finally,
you call the collect() function, which is
an action, to have it print out all the words
and its occurrences.
Again, you will get to work with this in the
lab exercises.