Passing functions to Spark. I wanted to touch
a little bit on this before we move further.
This is important to understand as you begin
to think about the business logic of your
application.
The design of Spark's API relies heavily on
passing functions in the driver program to
run on the cluster. When a job is executed,
the Spark driver needs to tell its worker
how to process the data.
There are three methods that you can use to
pass functions.
The first method to do this is using an anonymous
function syntax. You saw briefly what an anonymous
function is in the first lesson. This is useful
for short pieces of code. For example, here
we define the anonymous function that takes
in a particular parameter x of type Int and
add one to it. Essentially, anonymous functions
are useful for one-time use of the function.
In other words, you don't need to explicitly
define the function to use it. You define
it as you go. Again, the left side of the
=> are the parameters or the arguments. The
right side of the => is the body of the function.
Another method to pass functions around Spark
is to use static methods in a global singleton
object. This means that you can create a global
object, in the example, it is the object MyFunctions.
Inside that object, you basically define the
function func1. When the driver requires that
function, it only needs to send out the object
-- the worker will be able to access it. In
this case, when the driver sends out the instructions
to the worker, it just has to send out the
singleton object.
It is possible to pass reference to a method
in a class instance, as opposed to a singleton
object. This would require sending the object
that contains the class along with the method.
To avoid this consider copying it to a local
variable within the function instead of accessing
it externally.
Example, say you have a field with the string
Hello. You want to avoid calling that directly
inside a function as shown on the slide as
x => field + x.
Instead, assign it to a local variable so
that only the reference is passed along and
not the entire object shown val field_ = this.field.
For an example such as this, it may seem trivial,
but imagine if the field object is not a simple
text Hello, but is something much larger,
say a large log file. In that case, passing
by reference will have greater value by saving
a lot of storage by not having to pass the
entire file.
Back to our regularly scheduled program.
At this point, you should know how to link
dependencies with Spark and also know how
to initialize the SparkContext. I also touched
a little bit on passing functions with Spark
to give you a better view of how you can program
your business logic. This course will not
focus too much on how to program business
logics, but there are examples available for
you to see how it is done. The purpose is
to show you how you can create an application
using a simple, but effective example which
demonstrates Spark's capabilities.
Once you have the beginning of your application
ready by creating the SparkContext object,
you can start to program in the business logic
using Spark's API available in Scala, Java,
or Python. You create the RDD from an external
dataset or from an existing RDD. You use transformations
and actions to compute the business logic.
You can take advantage of RDD persistence,
broadcast variables and/or accumulators to
improve the performance of your jobs.
Here's a sample Scala application. You have
your import statement. After the beginning
of the object, you see that the SparkConf
is created with the application name. Then
a SparkContext is created. The several lines
of code after is creating the RDD from a text
file and then performing the Hdfs test on
it to see how long the iteration through the
file takes. Finally, at the end, you stop
the SparkContext by calling the stop() function.
Again, just a simple example to show how you
would create a Spark application. You will
get to practice this in the lab exercise.
I mentioned that there are examples available
which shows the various usage of Spark. Depending
on your programming language preference, there
are examples in all three languages that work
with Spark. You can view the source code of
the examples on the Spark website or within
the Spark distribution itself. I provided
some screenshots here to show you some of
the examples available.
On the slide, I also listed the step to run
these examples. To run Scala or Java examples,
you would execute the run-example script under
the Spark's home/bin directory. So for example,
to run the SparkPi application, execute run-example
SparkPi, where SparkPi would be the name of
the application. Substitute that with a different
application name to run that other application.
To run the sample Python applications, use
the spark-submit command and provide the path
to the application.