Hi. Welcome to the Spark Fundamentals course.
This lesson will cover Spark application programming.
After completing this lesson, you should be
able to understand the purpose and usage of
the SparkContext.This lesson will show you
how to can get started by programming your
own Spark application. First you will see
how to link to Spark. Next you will see how
to run some Spark examples. You should also
be able to understand how to pass functions
to Spark and be able to create and run a Spark
standalone application. Finally, you should
be able to submit applications to the Spark
cluster.
The SparkContext is the main entry point to
everything Spark. It can be used to create
RDDs and shared variables on the cluster.
When you start up the Spark Shell, the SparkContext
is automatically initialized for you with
the variable sc. For a Spark application,
you must first import some classes and implicit
conversions and then create the SparkContext
object. The three import statements for Scala
are shown on the slide here.
Each Spark application you create requires
certain dependencies. The next three slides
will show you how to link to those dependencies
depending on which programming language you
decide to use.
To link with Spark using Scala, you must have
a compatible version of Scala with the Spark
you choose to use. For example, Spark 1.1.1
uses Scala 2.10, so make sure that you have
Scala 2.10 if you wish to write applications
for Spark 1.1.1.
To write a Spark application, you must add
a Maven dependency on Spark. The information
is shown on the slide here. If you wish to
access a Hadoop cluster, you need to add a
dependency to that as well.
In the lab environment, this is already set
up for you. The information on this page shows
how you would set up for your own Spark cluster.
Spark 1.1.1 works with Python 2.6 or higher,
but not Python 3. It uses the standard CPython
interpreter, so C libraries like NumPy can
be used.
To run Spark applications in Python, use the
bin/spark-submit script located in the Spark's
home directory. This script will load the
Spark's Java/Scala libraries and allow you
to submit applications to a cluster. If you
wish to use HDFS, you will have to link to
it as well. In the lab environment, you will
not need to do this as Spark is bundled with
it. You also need to import some Spark classes
shown here.
Spark 1.1.1 works with Java 6 and higher.
If you are using Java 8, Spark supports lambda
expressions for concisely writing functions.
Otherwise, you can use the org.apache.spark.api.java.function
package with older Java versions.
As with Scala, you need to a dependency on
Spark, which is available through Maven Central.
If you wish to access an HDFS cluster, you
must add the dependency there as well. Last,
but not least, you need to import some Spark
classes.
Once you have the dependencies established,
the first thing is to do in your Spark application
before you can initialize Spark is to build
a SparkConf object. This object contains information
about your application.
For example, val conf = new SparkConf().setAppName(appName).setMaster(master).
You set the application name and tell it which
is the master node. The master parameter can
be a standalone Spark distribution, Mesos,
or a YARN cluster URL. You can also decide
to use the local keyword string to run it
in local mode. In fact, you can run local[16]
to specify the number of cores to allocate
for that particular job or Spark shell as
16.
For production mode, you would not want to
hardcode the master path in your program.
Instead, launch it as an argument to the spark-submit
command.
Once you have the SparkConf all set up, you
pass it as a parameter to the SparkContext
constructor to create the SparkContext
Here's the information for Python. It is pretty
much the same information as Scala. The syntax
here is slightly different, otherwise, you
are required to set up a SparkConf object
to pass as a parameter to the SparkContext
object. You are also recommended to pass the
master parameter as an argument to the spark-submit
operation.
Here's the same information for Java. Same
idea, you need to create the SparkConf object
and pass that to the SparkContext, which in
this case, would be a JavaSparkContext. Remember,
when you imported statements in the program,
you imported the JavaSparkContext libraries.