So for this last section, we're going to
talk briefly about
Spark caching. Spark caching is useful to
access repeated data much quicker
Both Python and Scala uses the same commands,
so we can input the following
commands in any of these two shells
so as a simple example we're going to
mark our linesWithSpark dataset, the
one we created earlier
to cache. Now remember when we do that is only a transformation action
or transformation operation, I should say, so it hasn't been cached yet. I have to
run some type of action. In this case, I'm going to call count().
so the first count() was invoked
and that counts and returns a value but also caches
the dataset. Then you run the count() again
the second time around you notice it'll
be a little bit faster, but again we're
working with a small small small dataset
so you won't see much changed but if the
dataset is indeed very large
then caching would provide a lot of benefits. This concludes this
lab exercise 1. Go ahead and quit out
of both of these shells, by using the CTRL+D
key combination. That is going to stop
everything.