In this section, you'll be
creating a sample application using
Scala.
You are going to be using a subset all the data for taxi trips
that will determine the top 10 medallion
numbers
based on the number of trips. I'm just cleaning up and closing all the windows
now.
and you can start a new one.
So for this exercise you are going to have to load
two additional taxi data into the
HDFS.
and it will be under the /tmp directory
so let's go ahead in create
two additional directories. So I am creating a
lab data directory, under the /tmp, I'm
going to create a
sparkdata directory under that labdata
directory
You can, of course, chain this together
into one command, but I wanted to show you
separately. Now you are going to upload
3 CSV file under the sparkdata
directory namely nyctaxi.csv
nyctaxisub.csv
and the nycweather.scv. We're going to use three hadoop
commands to put the files on the
HDFS under the sparkdata directory. So
the taxi data
is actually some taxi information from New York
and that data is going to get loaded onto
the HDFS. It is going to take a while
The file is actually quite big.
We're going to load in the taxisub
data. This is a subset
of the original one so we're going to
use original one
for this particular application and then
the other two will be used
for a later exercise but we're just loading all three of them now.
and then finally the nycweather.
Let's make sure that all the files were
successfully loaded.
Do a listing on the sparkdata directory.
alright everything look okay
Let's start up the Spark shell.
The first thing you are going to do is create the RDD
of the NYC taxi file. Everything
we do in Spark is going to consist of an RDD. If you wanted to,
you can take a look at the first five rows of content.
Use the take(5) method and print it to the console.
Essentially
once you print it out you are going to see the header columns
and the data after the
header so there's information like the medallion, the passenger count,
pick-up date/time, pick-up location
latitude/longitude.
Typically,
we will want to remove the header from the file, but because the operation
that we're going to be doing won't get affected by the header,
we're going to leave it in there -- it's not a
big deal. Also,
when you load in some type of input file,
you are going to want to
-- it's going to through each of these different columns here
With this information,
you can determine the medallion number
and the number based on a number
trips --
the top 10 medallion numbers based on the number trips. That's what we're going to find out here in
this lab exercise.
So now you going to parse the information up. Split it up by
commas. That is going to be a parsed -- merging up the data so that
way we can work with it. Next, you are
going to want to create some key/value
pairs from the
data with the key is the medallion and the value is one.
So we are going to use this model to alter sum up
all the keys to find a number trips a
particular
taxi took and in particular we will be
able to see which taxi
took the most trips. Here we are.
We are going to parse it up further to get out the key
and val(6) is the medallion
number and val(1) corresponds to the
the value basically mapping
the key to the value of 1.
Next we're going do the reduceByKey
function and that is going to add up all the
keys for a particular
taxi, so we going to see how many
times this taxi was recorded.
The values are actually swapped
when they come out, so we have to reorder them in descending order
so that the results can be presented
correctly so that's what this line here
is
doing is gonna swap it back around and
you're going to get the top 10 of it
and then have it printed out to the console with the formatting here
so you see in a second what that looks
like once it comes up.
so you can see the different medallions,  the number
and the number of trips they took and we
were
able to sort it by the top 10 so this
medallion
at the top had 415 trips the second one had 411 trips,
so on and so forth and the other steps
above we did,
we did on separate lines. You can
obviously chain everything together
and use a shorthand notation so here's
what I'm showing now
putting everything on one line, doing
the splitting
by the comma, the mapping of the medallion keys to one and then reducing by the key.
Obviously, in an actual application you
are going to want to be concise, but for debugging
purposes
it might be useful to break up the
individual operations
I'm just running the same
print statement out on the single line to
show you that they will produce the same
results.
You see the values within this
info
printed it here. Scroll up a little bit and you'll see the top --
actually, it is right there. The 415 trips
for the first medallion.
Just one line above the 411
and that's just due to the printouts of the logs.
Went ahead and cached the taxi
medallion one-line count. You run
the count on it to actually invoke the cache and you can run it again
to see that it is indeed faster because
it ran against the cache
but again not by much.  I we had more
data
obviously it will make more of a
difference.