In the next section of this exercise, you're
going to be joining our RDDs together.
So this would be some new operations
that will allow you to work with RDDs
We're going to join the readme
and the changes file. Both of these files
have been copied
into HDFS so let's create the RDD
for them. I just created the RDD for the readme.
Now I'm gonna create one for the changes file.
Take a look to see how many spark
keywords are in each
file. We're going to run the filter
command and we're going to look for the line
that contains the word spark and we're going to count it.
Then do the same thing for the changes
file. How many spark
keywords are in that?
Now let's do a word count on each of the RDD
so that the results will give you the
key-value pairs.
Essentially the number of occurrences for each words in each of the file.
We will start with the readme file first.
I'm going to call the readme.count().That is going to invoke
the flatMap operation to split up the
words
from the line so essentially we will have
one word per line
and then we're going to map each word to the value of
one, from which we can reduce by key
and here you see the shorthand notation
for the reduce by key.
Essentially we're going to add
the values of the two keys together to
get the final count.
So when this is done across the worker
nodes in the cluster, it is going to be
done in parallel
So you get a word count of that readme
file. Let's do the exact same thing
for the changes.txt file.
Breaking up the words
from the line to have individual words per
line
and then mapping each word to the value
and finally reducing it by the key to do
a count of the number of words.
To view each of the files individually,
the word counts, we'll just call the collect
operation to give you the list of words
words and their counts. The same thing can be done for the changes
RDD. Now, why don't we join these two together to
get a collective word count. To join the
RDDs
you are going to use the join function. The join function will essentially take
the key/value from one and add
the key/value from another to get
key and then the two values next each
other.
This the default action that is taken
in a join operation. I'm creating a
joinedRDD
readmeCount. The first RDD dot join
changes count, which is the second RDD
so that creates the joined RDD.
Then I want to cache our RDD.
and I'll print everything out onto the console. I'm going to call joined.collect().foreach()
I'm going to iterate through
and print onto the console.
So you see here the key and then
is the key value pair of the values. For
example in the word
print, appeared one time in the readme
file
and five times in the changes file.
This is the default operation of the join. What if you want to combine
for example, the two values
and add them up. That might be more useful, so
the next step we're going to combine these values.
Going to show you the key and then the
combined sum from the two values of the joined dataset.
I'll create a new RDD, called joinedSum
that's going to do a map
operation and so for each key,
I'm going to grab the first index so
._1 , which grabs the value of the first index
of the original dataset.
and then we're going to map it back out the way it is. So this is the key. We are going to
print the key out
and then for the value, we are going to do some addition on it. On the second
index is actually an index of an array,
that's why I can invoke the k._2
and then so in this case
(1,1) is an array. So I want the first value of that array
which is
._1
and I want the value of the 2nd array, which is
again, the 2nd index, is the k._2
which is an array and then you going to call the second index of the array, which is
._2 So it is ._1 + ._2
and you add it together. So that is the
RDD, which is called joinedSum.
Again, that's the key, and we have the elements of the first array, and then the
second elements of the array added together. We're adding both keys.
Both values to the keys together. Let's call the collect to take a look.
So check it out, now we know that the values of CLI
appears five times across both
files and basically everything else shows you
the combined
values. You want to make sure it's
correct, you can
do a take(5) which grabs the first
five elements
of the original joined and I want
print it to the
console. Then I'll be doing the same thing
for the joinedSum, which is the combined one,
to see that the values have been indeed
been added together correctly. so CLI
was (1,4)
now CLI is 5 and you can see how
all the values are added together correctly.