So now, we're going to do the same tasks
using Python. We're done with Scala, you can open up a
new terminal or close the other one, it's up to you. Open up a new terminal
and start up the pyspark shell
located under the spark_home/
/bin directory.
Now, you are going to create the RDD of the log file
from the first exercise. The log file
was called sparkLog.out, so go ahead
and create the RDD for that.
Next filter
out the lines that contains the keyword
'info'
from the log file.
And then get the count of the number lines with the word info in it.
Remember, your results will be different
from what I have as we probably loaded
different log files.
You can always chain
operations together so here we filter
and do a count
to find a number of
Spark in the lines. You can also do a
collect
to have it print out the lines
that fits the filters criteria.
And finally you can also view the DAG
of an RDD using the toDebugString().
Now we are going to get into joining RDDs
in Python. As you have done before
it's going to be the same you have to
create the two RDD's for the readme
file
and the changes.txt file.
Let's find out how many spark keywords are in each file
but filtering out and then doing a count
on it.
Do the same thing for the changes file.
Let's do a word count to get the number
words and their occurrences
in each of the RDD. First,
you do the flattmap operation to break
up the words into their own line
and then you map the words to the value
and then you reduce by that key to add up all the number up occurrences of a
particular word.
Let's do the same for the changes.txt file.
likewise you can do the collect
operation on it to see the
actual word count of each of the files.
So now let's just join
these two datasets together to produce a collective word count
from both files. So if the words are the same, they will be counted and added together.
We are going to use the
join operation. So create a
joined RDD and then the first RRD.join
to the 2nd RDD. Let's go ahead and cache
this RDD and the print
the value out to the console. So each key
is followed by
an array of the values for that particular key
or the word.
Now just like with Scala, we are going to combine it. So we're going to run an operation to
add the sums to the values together for a
particular key, so instead of seeing
a key with an array of values, you are going to see a
key with the total sum of the value, so
that's what we just did
to have a joinedSum. Now are going to do the take(5) to get the first five values
from each set -- the old
set and the new set in order to compare
the sums of these two. You see that they both
are equal, indicating that the operation
completed successfully.
Now we are going to get into shared variables. Pythons also has these two shared variables
available with Spark or
rather Spark has
these shared variables available with Python. Broadcast variables
is the first one. You created the same
way using the Spark Context.
and these broadcast variables are useful for when the datasets gets really large
so you don't have to send each of the dataset out to the worker nodes,
rather you just out the broadcast value
and then the worker nodes just invoke the .value()
operation to grab the values. Then,
accumulators, on the other hand, can only be added
through as associative operation by a worker node.
Again creating an accumulator
values starts at 0.
and then we are going to test this out by creating an RDD
with the values one two three and four. Then we are going to define a function
which will add in the values as a
given array into
the accumulator. Here I am defining the
accumulator
and I'm going to add each value of the
element into the accumulator.
Then iterate through
each element of the original RDD, the one with the values one through four
and pass in that function we just created.
So the function will
take each value of the array and add it to
the accumulator.
and we need to call out the accum.value() to see the value of the
accumulator.
Remember, only be driver node
can access the value of the accumulator.
Worker nodes can only
add to it. They cannot see the value. Finally,
again a quick part on the key/value pairs.
We have seen this already with
the joining of the RDDs in Python
but it is zero-indexed, so pair[0] will give you the first element and pair[1] will
give you the second.