Now we are going to run an application well create and run an application using Python.
Python is actually a bit simpler.
You don't need to build up the classes
unless you have some external library or
dependencies.
First thing you will do is
going to open up the terminal. Then we're going to create the
new directory under the virtuer. We are going to call it PythonPi.
Again we're going to calculate the Pi, the value of Pi
using Python.
Create a PythonPy.py file.
Go ahead and paste the code into this
terminal. You are going to open it
up and then go through the lines -- what each of the
lines mean, but remember this again is just to show you
the Spark related stuff. We have to import
some
libraries. Obviously the Spark context
is important. We're creating a Spark context.
and this one we provide the application name directly into it.
and then these lines of codes are the business logic
required to calculate the value of pi.
Then finally we print the value of Pi to the console and then
again, we need to stop the Spark context.
So to run Python classes, you just
invoked the spark-submit script directly.
This is done under the $SPARK_HOME/bin directory.
You provide the parameter
for the local node to use
four cores, just like before and then just
provide
the PythonPi file. Scroll back up to
show you again this is the output that was calculated using this Python application.
Again you successfully created and
ran the file using a spark-submit
application
In this lab exercise,
you should be able to create and run
and link with Scala and Python applications.