In the next section of our lab
exercise, you are going to be creating a Spark application with
Spark Streaming. This section focuses on
Spark Streams -- an easy to build and
scalable
stream processing libraries. Stream jobs are written in the same way as Spark batch jobs
and they support Java, Scala and Python.
In this exercise, the taxi data trip
will be streamed using a socket
connection
and then analyzed to provide a summary
of the number passengers by taxi vendors
We're going to be using a
Spark shell with Scala. What I'm doing
here is creating a PythonStreams directory
under our /home/virtuser
and then I'm going to copy in from
from our labfiles directory into our PythonStreams
directory. I'm just moving some files around
so that we can have everything in one
location. The first file that I moved was the
nyctaxi100.csv
and then we have to the taxistreams.py file
The Python file will be the one that
actually pushes the CSV file
into a socket connection on port 7777.
so this will serve as our streaming
data set so we're doing a simulation
of the stream. Make sure you edit
the Python file -- the taxistream.py
to point to the correct location of your
taxi file.
Here I just need to change the location
to
the virtuser. This is where initially just
copy the
nyctaxi100 file. You can see that the port
and the host name and they were just going to print each row of the data that we
stream out so you see it on the console.
okay changing to that PythonStreams directory --
and then you're going to
run this taxistreams.py
while it runs here
it is going to wait for the spark streaming
application
so again when the Spark one starts up,
This python stream will feed
in the CSV file. So open up another terminal because this new terminal is
where we're going to write
the Spark application. Start up the Spark
shell
Because this program is going to
require you to view the content
on the console, we're going to turn off the logs so
these four lines of code will turn the logging off so that no logs will appear in the console
that'll make it a lot easier to see the
streaming content
that comes out so when the screen goes
through, the Spark application will grab
information -- basically define the number
passengers
per taxi vendor and it will print that to this console right here.
and now I just imported some libraries
for spark streaming and just like with
SparkSQL you're going to have to
create a streaming context
from the given spark context.
we're going to call this ssc.StreamContext
and the passing in the Spark context.
Again we're giving in an interval of one
second
for the batches to come in. This just
makes it easier for us to read
the stream as it comes through the
socket.
Now we have to create the socket stream
that connects
to the localhost on port 7777
so using the stream context
Here again -- this is the taxi stream that we will feed into that
socket that we are going to listen to.
The CSV file is going to be fed in
with the data -- that is just to simulate our stream,
again. Now we put in the business logic
to split up the lines on each comma
and then provide this information
to the spark streaming application so
that it can process and analyze the
stream
so we define the lines by mapping it
and splitting it on the comma.
and then pass(15) is the taxi vendor. pass(7)
is the passenger count for that vendor and then we're reducing it by the taxi vendor
to get the total count or the number of passengers per taxi.
Now this will tell us which taxi vendor had the most passengers.
We're going to have it print to the console.
But wait a second? Why didn't it print anything?
That's because in a stream supplication
a won't print anything until you
explicitly
tell it to print by using the start command to have it to start the stream.
Once that happens you see that
the
PythonStreams windows and this one is going to both run.
So copy and paste both of the lines in the lab exercise guide.
Make sure you do that, for both of them.
It will automatically start to listen to the
socket and then the Python streams will
begin by feeding in that CSV file.
Go ahead and copy/paste both lines at once
Then immediately you can see the Python stream
beginning to feed in the data and then it prints it out and then our
Scala terminal here, you see the
taxi vendor
and the number passengers for that vendor. This is simulating a stream
and showing you how spark streaming can be used to process a stream
and our processing here just creates
the analysis for the number of passengers.
You can quit the streams by doing
CTRL+C on each window to stop it.
This demonstrates that you have now
successfully created a spark streaming
application.