In this section of the lab exercise, you
going to be creating a Spark
application
using the MLlib library. In this
section
the Spark shell will be used to acquire
the k-means clustering
or drop off latitude and longitude of taxis for the three clusters.
You are going to see the sample dataset
that we've already uploaded on to HDFS
is going to contain
a subset of taxi trips with hack license,
medallions, pick up
date/time drop off date/time, passenger
information and so on and so forth
As such this may give you a good
indication
of where it is best to hail a cab. Like I said
we've already uploaded
this information or the CSV file in a
previous exercise.
It is located under the /tmp directory
labdata/sparkdata
so we can go take a look at
this and
kind of see what the input files like.
I'm going to end this Scala shell here
from the previous exercise. Start up with
a new shell
and if you want to you can take a
look
at what the data looks like. It's actually
quite a big file. In fact, even
it is a subset so using the nyctaxisub
which is just a subset of the full
set of data that we used from the last exercise. So you do this is actually
going to take a while
to load everything up, but it will you give you an idea of what the
datatype looks like, so we won't have to sit through this in a video.
I'm going to speed up the process.
You can see how the information on
here
just to get an idea of what it looks like
as you begin to use it with the MLlib library.
So let's start up to spark shell
as that where we are going to be writing our
Spark application.
First thing you need to do is import the necessary libraries
for the k-means algorithm and the vector packages. I went ahead and did that.
We're going to create an RDD from the data that already reside
in the HDFS. Normally when you import
data in
you want to see how big the file is and if
there's any way you can trim it --
trim unnecessary information. You should
do that prior to
any data processing as the full dataset may be
too large or takes too long with irrelevant information. So here is a
way to filter out on information. We just
want information for the year 2013
and of course we are going to split it up by the commas.
clean out some of the entries that we don't need. In fact,
this subset the data already contains
the filtered set, so that's why there are no
changes here
but if you ran this on the full set, you'll
end up with this subset.
So I went ahead and did that already, but that is just to show you that you should filter
it out.
Another thing we can do is to cleanse the
data even further by
just fencing
the information around to just New York
City, so that's what this
is doing here. We are just providing the
coordinates for New York City specifically and filter out data that
are only within the boundary so now if you do another count
you'll see that the number rows have
indeed been reduced
so it helps a little bit but now we have
a much
more specific set of data to work with
okay so next
you are going to want to create vectors
with the latitude and longitude
they'll be used as input to the
k-means algorithm
so this line here
is going to set up this vector for you. We're creating our taxi vector.
Then the next several lines of code we
will be
using to define and run the k-means algorithm.
So here's the iteration count, its going to be 10
plus the count of three. Then we are going to create our model
by providing the taxi,
the cluster count and the iteration count.
If you had used the larger
dataset, it would have taken probably up to ten minutes or so,
but this shorter one should have
been significantly faster.
In any case, we can now generate the
cluster center by providing in
that model and mapping into the array.
We have an array of cluster centers.
We're going to compute the cost
of these computations
and finally we have enough information
to print out
the coordinates so the
best locations within New York City to
hail a cab, so these are the most frequent
drop off points and
locations so now we have information
that we need
to indicate where its best to hail a cab.
So now you have seen how to use the
k-means algorithm
as part of the MLlib libraries. There are other libraries within MLlib,
so be sure to check those out. This concludes this portion of the lab exercise.