So now let's get into the last
section of this exercise
and that is to create a Spark
application using the GraphX library --
a graph processing library. Now this one is going to be a short lab exercise
but for this exercise you will need to
copy the users.txt and followers.txt from the local VM to the HDFS
under the virtuser directory. First command here is to copy the users.txt
over to the /tmp directory on HDFS -- and the second one is going to copy the followers
so the application here is
to rank the users based on the
number of followers they have
so we have some sample uses listed and
also some followers
so we're going to use some graph processing library.
namely GraphX with Spark to compute this
Here I let you take a look at some of the
sample users
and then you can take a look at the
followers for those particular users.
Now we're going to do a ranking of them using a page
rank alrogithm that comes with a
GraphX
library. There are additional libraries to use. Again this is just a sample
application
to show you how you will utilize a
library from the GraphX.
We're going to start up a Spark shell.
Obviously if you're writing a production
application you going to
use it in a Java or Scala
or Python application and not doing the shell. The shell is just a quick and dirty
way for us to
learn about the library.
So here I went ahead and created the
user's RDD
and did some transformation on it. In
fact
I was supposed to import the GraphX library
prior to this, but because we're just
creating the RDD and not doing anything
with GraphX yet
it actually went through and everything is ok.
So now go ahead and import the GraphX library,
which usually should be the first thing
you do I just overlooked this particular
step.
but not a big deal. The line after that
is to create a graph of the followers.
so I'm creating a followers graph based
on the text file.
Now we have an RDD
of users and a followers graph.
You can see that it took about 425 seconds to load the edges.
Next we are going to parse
the data and then attach the user's
attributes
together. This is just some business
logic to attach
the user's attributes to the graph
and then we're going to create a
subgraph to restrict it with only
username
and the names. Now we compute the
page rank to get the information they
we're looking for.
so this is using the heart of the GraphX library
to compute the page rank and once that
comes out
we will have the information we need to
grab the attributes
of the top pagerank users.
Here we will paste in the commands
to grab the attributes of our top pagerank
user.
Then finally will have what we need
to print this information out to the
console.
We're gonna grab the top five
and do some ordering on it, and there you go.
This is the users and followers we rank them
using the pagerank algorithm from the
the GraphX library.
This concludes this lab exercise. You should now be able to
see how to use the GraphX library or
graph
processing scenario such as this.