Hi and welcome to the lab exercise 4: Working with the Spark libraries.
This exercise will show you how to
create various applications
using these libraries. The advantage of these libraries are that
they a tightly integrated with Spark
with little overhead as opposed to other
software
where you would have to integrate and
work with different 3rd party libraries.
This one, everything is bundled
together. Any updates or changes made to
the Spark core,
all these libraries will, in fact, get them as well.
The first section of this lab exercise, we're going to
create a Spark application with SparkSQL.
SparkSQL provides the ability to
write relational queries
to be run on Spark. There's the
abstraction schemaRDD,
which is used to create
an RDD that can run SQL, HiveQL, and Scala.
In this lab section you are going to use SQL to find out the average weather
and precipitation for a given time
period in New York.
Again the purpose is to demonstrate how
to use
the SparkSQL libraries on Spark.
So our nycweather data
is already on the HDFS under /tmp/labdata/sparkdata/
You uploaded this in a previous lab exercise. Go ahead and take a look
at this data. We're doing a Hadoop
command to view the contents of nycweather.csv
so there are three columns here you have
the date
the mean temperature in Celsius and the
precipitation
for the day. Since we already know the
scheme here
we're going infer the schema using
reflection. So let's launch
the spark shell and get started with this
exercise.
The first thing you have to do is define
the SQLContext
from the existing SparkContext, so here I
am creating the SQLContext and I'm
passing
in sc which is the spark contenxt. We're
going to be doing
our work inside the SQLContext.
Now you are going to have to import
a schemaRDD. That's what we're doing
here. We are going to import a sqlConext.createSchemaRDD
This is going to allow
us to work with schema RDD
Next we're going to
work with a case class in Scala that defines
the schema type of the table. In this case we are going to call this
weather. The first column is going to be a
date
column with a string. Second column is an integer
for the Celsius and the third column is the precipitation
as a double.
We can create the RDD of the weather
object. So we are
loading in the text file using the
regular SparkContext
loading in this CSV file and then we are going to split up the files on the commas
For each value, we are going to map it to our
case class that we created in the
previous step. The first column
is going to come from w0. The second column is w1
and we're going to do a little trimming on it to make sure the data doesn't contain any
extra white spaces or anything like that.
So now at this point you're ready to
create and run some queries
on the RDD. So we have to register
this RDD as a table, so we just
invoked the registerTempTable
command, and give it the name of weather.
So that's going to be the name of the table when we run the
query against it. Now we can
run the query on it. We're going to
find
the hottest day with precipitation.
So I'm creating a hottest_with_precip
schemaRDD and it is going to come from SQLContxt and the next is
sql and then we put in the query right
inside. So I'm doing a select * on
the weather table -- that's the same table
that we
registered earlier and we're going to fidn where the precipitation is greater than
0 and we are going to
sort it by descending so the hottest
day is going to be on top.
You have the result set that as part of the
hottest_with_precip RDD.
We're going to go ahead and print this out
onto the console.
First we are going to map it to the
various column. I am going to have a date column with the first index
the value first index the temp column, the value of the second index the
precipitation.
Then we are going to get the top 10  dates and print it out to the console.
So there it is.
You saw how you can print it out the console. You can format it anyway you like,
but essentially what we've done here is
we took a
text file CSV, put into
a schemeRDD and ran queries against it. You can do this for any type
of business logic that your application
requires.