Welcome to the last lab exercise of this Spark course.
This is actually going to be a short exercise to
have you be able to configure and
monitor Spark applications.
So this will start you off to let you know
where and how you can configure and
monitor
Spark. So configuring Spark applications,
Spark properties control most
application settings and are configure
separately for each
application. These properties can be set
directly on the Spark configuration
object
and pass to your Spark Context. So you have seen this done in the Spark
applications.
You set up the SparkConf and you pass the
variable over to the Spark Context. You can also set properties during the run
time
and that done by providing into the
spark-submit
script. You've also seen how to do this
in a previous lab exercise.
In this section, we're going to take a look at some common
Spark properties that are the defaults. This is here inside the
Spark-default properties and this one
actually has the lowest precedence.
So properties sent directly on the
SparkConf or
the Spark configuration object takes
priority number one
and any flags passed in the spark-submit script
is priority number two and finally
you don't have anything set this is where all
the defaults
are located. So you can modify this under
the spark-defaults.conf
located under
the spark configuration directory.
So this is just show you
quickly how you can set different
configurations based on what you need to
do
Now I'm going to show you how to monitor Spark
applications via the Ambari console.
Just log in to localhost on 8080 and the
log in to the Ambari console is admin
user ID and admin the password.
So here is
the dashboard and others services that
are available here
See the different components available.
You can monitor your entire cluster
through this Ambari console. I clicked on the
spark cluster on the spark component and see everything is good.
Under quick links there's the spark job
history user interface
This basically shows you all the Spark
applications that you have ran.
Obviously it'll be slightly different
from what you see.
We're now going to do a quick
exercise to show you
how the monitoring can be done using
caching. If you are going to cache some data, you will want to see how much memory is
being stored as part of the cache.
I'm going to start up the spark shell.
Then create the RDD from the readme file.
Cache that readme file and then run the
collect operation to
invoke the caching as well. Remember,
actions are the ones that invokes
and performs the actual activity. So I
went ahead and quickly quit the Spark shell
You need to quit it so it will appear on the
history server.
and then now on this going back to the
history server
you can actually just refresh the page. It will show up. I want to make sure it
shows up.
Here you see the first entry is the shell that we just ran.
You click on it, you see the
details for the jobs.
Up above, you click on stages
you see the different stages for all
jobs.
Under storage is where you see the readme file
and how much memory it was used to
store that
file so if your dataset is really large, you may consider creating a broadcast variable
so this is how monitoring can help you.
you determine
how to make your application is more
with memory efficient. That's basically
what I want show in this lab exercise.
on how the Ambari console looks like -- where
the configuration file can be set. This concludes
this lab exercise. I hope you enjoy the
course
and stay tuned for future courses.