Spark streaming gives you the capability to
process live streaming data in small batches.
Utilizing Spark's core, Spark Streaming is
scalable, high-throughput and fault-tolerant.
You write Stream programs with DStreams, which
is a sequence of RDDs from a stream of data.
There are various data sources that Spark
Streaming receives from including, Kafka,
Flume, HDFS, Kinesis, or Twitter. It pushes
data out to HDFS, databases, or some sort
of dashboard.
Spark Streaming supports Scala, Java and Python.
Python was actually introduced with Spark
1.2. Python has all the transformations that
Scala and Java have with DStreams, but it
can only support text data types. Support
for other sources such as Kafka and Flume
will be available in future releases for Python.
Here's a quick view of how Spark Streaming
works. First the input stream comes in to
Spark Streaming. Then that data stream is
broken up into batches of data that is fed
into the Spark engine for processing. Once
the data has been processed, it is sent out
in batches.
Spark Stream support sliding window operations.
In a windowed computation, every time the
window slides over a source of DStream, the
source RDDs that falls within the window are
combined and operated upon to produce the
resulting RDD.
There are two parameters for a sliding window.
The window length is the duration of the window
and the sliding interval is the interval in
which the window operation is performed. Both
of these must be in multiples of the batch
interval of the source DStream.
In the diagram, the window length is 3 and
the sliding interval is 2. To put it in a
different perspective, say you wanted to generate
word counts over last 30 seconds of data,
every 10 seconds. To do this, you would apply
the reduceByKeyAndWindow operation on the
pairs of DStream of (Word,1) pairs over the
last 30 seconds of data.
Here we a have a simple example. We want to
count the number of words coming in from the
TCP socket. First and foremost, you must import
the appropriate libraries. Then, you would
create the StreamingContext object. In it,
you specify to use two threads with the batch
interval of 1 second. Next, you create the
DStream, which is a sequence of RDDs, that
listens to the TCP socket on the given hostname
and port. Each record of the DStream is a
line of text. You split up the lines into
individual words using the flatMap function.
The flatMap function is a one-to-many DStream
operation that takes one line and creates
a new DStream by generating multiple records
(in our case, that would be the words on the
line). Finally, with the words DStream, you
can count the words using the map and reduce
model. Then you print out the results to the
console.
One thing to note is that when each element
of the application is executed, the real processing
doesn't actually happen yet. You have to explicitly
tell it to start. Once the application begins,
it will continue running until the computation
terminates. The code snippets that you see
here is from a full sample found in the NetworkWordCount.
To run the full example, you must first start
up netcat, which is a small utility found
in most Unix-like systems. This will act as
a data source to give the application streams
of data to work with. Then, on a different
terminal window, run the application using
the command shown here.