In the next three slides, you will see another
example of creating a Spark application. First
you will see how to do this in Scala. The
next following sets of slides will show Python
and Java.
The application shown here counts the number
of lines with 'a' and the number of lines
with 'b'. You will need to replace the YOUR_SPARK_HOME
with the directory where Spark is installed,
if you wish to code this application.
Unlike the Spark shell, you have to initialize
the SparkContext in a program. First you must
create a SparkConf to set up your application's
name. Then you create the SparkContext by
passing in the SparkConf object. Next, you
create the RDD by loading in the textFile,
and then caching the RDD. Since we will be
applying a couple of transformations on it,
caching will help speed up the process, especially
if the logData RDD is large. Finally, you
get the values of the RDD by executing the
count action on it. End the program by printing
it out onto the console.
In Python, this application does the exact
same thing, that is, count the number of lines
with 'a' in it, and the number of lines with
'b' in it. You use a SparkContext object to
create the RDDs and cache it. Then you run
the transformations and actions, follow by
a print to the console. Nothing entirely new
here, just a difference in syntax.
Similar to Scala and Python, in Java you need
to get a JavaSparkContext. RDDs are represented
by JavaRDD. Then you run the transformations
and actions on them. The lambda expressions
of Java 8 allows you to concisely write functions.
Otherwise, you can use the classes in the
org.apache.spark.api.java.function package
for older versions of java. The business logic
is the same as the previous two examples to
count the number of a's and b's from the Readme
file. Just a matter of difference in the syntax
and library names.
Up until this point, you should know how to
create a Spark application using any of the
supported programming languages. Now you get
to see how to run the application. You will
need to first define the dependencies. Then
you have to package the application together
using system build tools such as Ant, sbt,
or Maven. The examples here show how you would
do it using the various tools. You can use
any tool for any of the programming languages.
For Scala, the example is shown using sbt,
so you would have a simple.sbt file. In Java,
the example shows using Maven so you would
have the pom.xml file. In Python, if you need
to have dependencies that requires third party
libraries, then you can use the --py-files
argument to handle that.
Again, shown here are examples of what a typical
directory structure would look like for the
tool that you choose.
Finally, once you have the JAR packaged created,
run the spark-submit to execute the application.
In the lab exercise, you will get to practice
this.
In short, you package up your application
into a JAR for Scala or Java or a set of .py
or .zip files for Python.
To submit your application to the Spark cluster,
you use spark-submit command, which is located
under the $SPARK_HOME/bin directory.
The options shown on the slide are the commonly
used options. To see other options, just invoke
spark-submit with the help argument.
Let's briefly go over what each of these options
mean.
The class option is the main entry point to
your class. If it is under a package name,
you must provide the fully qualified name.
The master URL is where your cluster is located.
Remember that it is recommended approach to
provide the master URL here, instead of hardcoding
it in your application code.
The deploy-mode is whether you want to deploy
your driver on the worker nodes (cluster)
or locally as an external client (client).
The default deploy-mode is client.
The conf option is any configuration property
you wish to set in key=value format.
The application jar is the file that you packaged
up using one of the build tools.
Finally, if the application has any arguments,
you would supply it after the jar file.
Here's an actual example of running a Spark
application locally on 8 cores. The class
is the org.apache.spark.examples.SparkPi.
local[8] is saying to run it locally on 8
cores. The examples.jar is located on the
given path with the argument 100 to be passed
into the SparkPi application.
Having completed this lesson, you should now
know how to create a standalone Spark application
and run it by submitting it to the Spark Cluster.
You saw briefly on the different methods on
how to pass functions in Spark. All three
programming languages were shown in this lesson.
Next steps. Copmlete lab exercise #3, Creating
a Spark application and then proceed to the
next lesson in this course.