Hi. Welcome to the Spark Fundamentals course.
This lesson will cover Spark configuration,
monitoring and tuning.
After completing this lesson, you should be
able describe the cluster overview. Configure
Spark by modifying Spark properties, environmental
variables or logging properties. Monitor Spark
and its applications using the Web UIs, metrics
and various other external tools. Also covered
in this lesson would be some performance tuning
considerations.
There are three main components of a Spark
cluster. You have the driver, where the SparkContext
is located within the main program. To run
on a cluster, you would need some sort of
cluster manager. This could be either Spark's
standalone cluster manager, Mesos or Yarn.
Then you have your worker nodes where the
executor resides. The executors are the processes
that run computations and store the data for
the application. The SparkContext sends the
application, defined as JAR or Python files
to each executor. Finally, it sends the tasks
for each executor to run.
Several things to understand about this architecture.
Each application gets its own executor. The
executor stays up for the entire duration
of the application. The benefit of this is
that the applications are isolated from each
other, on the scheduling side and running
on different JVMs. However, this means that
you cannot share data across applications.
You would need to externalize the data if
you wish to share data between thedifferent
applications.
Spark applications don't care about the underlying
cluster manager. As long as it can acquire
executors and communicate with each other,
it can run on any cluster manager.
Because the driver program schedules tasks
on the cluster, it should run close to the
worker nodes on the same local network. If
you like to send remote requests to the cluster,
it is better to use a RPC and have it submit
operations from nearby.
There are currently three supported cluster
managers that we have mentioned before. Sparks
comes with a standalone manager that you can
use to get up and running. You can use Apache
Mesos, a general cluster manager that can
run and service Hadoop jobs. Finally, you
can also use Hadoop YARN, the resource manager
in Hadoop 2. In the lab exercise, you will
be using BigInsights with Yarn to run your
Spark applications.
Spark configuration.
There are three main locations for Spark configuration.
You have the Spark properties, where the application
parameters can be set using the SparkConf
object or through Java system properties.
Then you have the environment variables, which
can be used to set per machine settings such
as IP address. This is done through the conf/spark-env.sh
script on each node.
Finally, you also have your logging properties,
which can be configured through log4j.properties.
You can choose to override the default configuration
directory, which is currently under the SPARK_HOME/conf
directory. Set the SPARK_CONF_DIR environment
variable and provide your custom configuration
files under that directory.
In the lab exercise, the Spark shell can be
verbose, so if you wish, change it from INFO
to ERROR in the log4j.properties to reduce
all the information being printed on the console.
There are two methods of setting Spark properties.
The first method is by passing application
properties via the SparkConf object. As you
know, the SparkConf variable is used to create
the SparkContext object. In the example shown
on this slide, you set the master node as
local, the appName as "CountingSheep", and
you allow 1GB for each of the executor processes.
The second method is to dynamically set the
Spark properties. Spark allows you to pass
in an empty SparkConf when creating the SparkContext
as shown on the slide.
You can then either supply the values during
runtime by using the command line options
--master or the --conf. You can see the list
of options using the --help when executing
the spark-submit script.
On the slide here, you give the app name of
My App and telling it to run on the local
system with four cores. You set the spark.shuffle.spill
to false and the various java options at the
end. Finally you supply the application JAR
file after all the properties have been specified.
You can find a list of all the properties
on the spark.apache.org website.
Another way to set Spark properties is to
provide your settings inside the spark-defaults.conf
file. The spark-submit script will read in
the configurations from this file. You can
view the Spark properties on the application
web UI at the port 4040 by default.
One thing I'll add is that properties set
directly on the SparkConf take highest precedence,
then flags passed to spark-submit or spark-shell
is second and finally options in the spark-defaults.conf
file is the lowest priority.