Hi. Welcome to the Spark Fundamentals course.
This lesson will cover the Introduction to
the Spark libraries.
After completing this lesson, you should be
able to understand and use the various Spark
libraries including SparkSQL, Spark Streaming,
MLlib and GraphX
Spark comes with libraries that you can utilize
for specific use cases. These libraries are
an extension of the Spark Core API. Any improvements
made to the core will automatically take effect
with these libraries. One of the big benefits
of Spark is that there is little overhead
to use these libraries with Spark as they
are tightly integrated. The rest of this lesson
will cover on a high level, each of these
libraries and their capabilities. The main
focus will be on Scala with specific callouts
to Java or Python if there are major differences.
The four libraries are Spark SQL, Spark Streaming,
MLlib, and GraphX.
Spark SQL allows you to write relational queries
that are expressed in either SQL, HiveQL,
or Scala to be executed using Spark. Spark
SQL has a new RDD called the SchemaRDD. The
SchemaRDD consists of rows objects and a schema
that describes the type of data in each column
in the row. You can think of this as a table
in a traditional relational database.
You create a SchemaRDD from existing RDDs,
a Parquet file, a JSON dataset, or using HiveQL
to query against the data stored in Hive.
You can write Spark SQL application using
Scala, Java or Python.
The SQLContext is created from the SparkContext.
You can see here that in Scala, the sqlContext
is created from the SparkContext. In Java,
you create the JavaSQLContext from the JavaSparkContext.
In Python, you also do the same.
There is a new RDD, called the SchemaRDD that
you use with Spark SQL. In Scala only, you
have to import a library to convert an existing
RDD to a SchemaRDD. For the others, you do
not need to import a library to work with
the Schema RDD.
So how do these SchemaRDDs get created? There
are two ways you can do this.
The first method uses reflection to infer
the schema of the RDD. This leads to a more
concise code and works well when you already
know the schema while writing your Spark application.
The second method uses a programmatic interface
to construct a schema and then apply that
to an existing RDD. This method gives you
more control when you don't know the schema
of the RDD until runtime. The next two slides
will cover these two methods in more detail.
The first of the two methods used to determine
the schema of the RDD is to use reflection.
In this scenario, use the case class in Scala
to define the schema of the table. The arguments
of the case class are read using reflection
and becomes the names of the columns.
Let's go over the code shown on the slide.
First thing is to create the RDD of the person
object.
You load the text file in using the textFile
method. Then you invoke the map transformation
to split the elements on a comma to get the
individual columns of name and age. The final
transformation creates the Person object based
on the elements.
Next you register the people RDD that you
just created by loading in the text file and
performing the transformation as a table.
Once the RDD is a table, you use the sql method
provided by SQLContext to run SQL statements.
The example here selects from the people table,
the schemaRDD.
Finally, the results that comes out from the
select statement is also a SchemaRDD.
That RDD, teenagers on our slide, can run
normal RDD operations.
The programmatic interface is used when cannot
define the case classes ahead of time. For
example, when the structure of records is
encoded in a string or a text dataset will
be parsed and fields will be projected different
for different users.
A schemaRDD is created with three steps.
The first is to create an RDD of Rows from
the original RDD. In the example, we create
a schemaString of name and age.
The second step is to create the schema using
the RDD from step one. The schema is represented
by a StructType that takes the schemaString
from the first step and splits it up into
StructFields. In the example, the schema is
created using the StructType by splitting
the name and age schemaString and mapping
it to the StructFields, name and age.
The third step convert records of the RDD
of people to Row objects. Then you apply the
schema to the row RDD.
Once you have your SchemaRDD, you register
that RDD as a table and then you run sql statements
against it using the sql method.
The results are returned as the SchemaRDD
and you can run any normal RDD operation on
it. In the example, we select the name from
the people table, which is the SchemaRDD.
Then we print it out on the console.