Now I want to get a bit into RDD persistence.
You have seen this used already. That is the
cache function. The cache function is actually
the default of the persist function with the
MEMORY_ONLY storage.
One of the key capability of Spark is its
speed through persisting or caching. Each
node stores any partitions of the cache and
computes it in memory. When a subsequent action
is called on the same dataset, or a derived
dataset, it uses it from memory instead of
having to retrieve it again. Future actions
in such cases are often 10 times faster. The
first time a RDD is persisted, it is kept
in memory on the node. Caching is fault tolerant
because if it any of the partition is lost,
it will automatically be recomputed using
the transformations that originally created
it.
There are two methods to invoke RDD persistence.
persist() and cache(). The persist() method
allows you to specify a different storage
level of caching. For example, you can choose
to persist the data set on disk, persist it
in memory but as serialized objects to save
space, etc. Again the cache() method is just
the default way of using persistence by storing
deserialized objects in memory.
The table here shows the storage levels and
what it means. Basically, you can choose to
store in memory or memory and disk. If a partition
does not fit in the specified cache location,
then it will be recomputed on the fly. You
can also decide to serialized the objects
before storing this. This is space efficient,
but will require the RDD to deserialized before
it can be read, so it takes up more CPU workload.
There's also the option to replicate each
partition on two cluster nodes. Finally, there
is an experimental storage level storing the
serialized object in Tachyon. This level reduces
garbage collection overhead and allows the
executors to be smaller and to share a pool
of memory. You can read more about this on
Spark's website.
A lot of text on this page, but don't worry.
It can be used as a reference when you have
to decide the type of storage level.
There are tradeoffs between the different
storage levels. You should analyze your current
situation to decide which level works best.
You can find this information here on Spark's
website.
Basically if your RDD fits within the default
storage level, by all means, use that.
It is the fastest option to fully take advantage
of Spark's design. If not, you can serialized
the RDD and use the MEMORY_ONLY_SER level.
Just be sure to choose a fast serialization
library to make the objects more space efficient
and still reasonably fast to access.
Don't spill to disk unless the functions that
compute your datasets are expensive or it
requires a large amount of space.
If you want fast recovery, use the replicated
storage levels. All levels are fully fault
tolerant, but would still require the recomputing
of the data. If you have a replicated copy,
you can continue to work while Spark is reconstruction
a lost partition.
Finally, use Tachyon if your environment has
high amounts of memory or multiple applications.
It allows you to share the same pool of memory
and significantly reduces garbage collection
costs. Also, the cached data is not lost if
the individual executors crash.
On these last two slides, I'll talk about
Spark's shared variables and the type of operations
you can do on key-value pairs.
Spark provides two limited types of shared
variables for common usage patterns: broadcast
variables and accumulators. Normally, when
a function is passed from the driver to a
worker, a separate copy of the variables are
used for each worker. Broadcast variables
allow each machine to work with a read-only
variable cached on each machine. Spark attempts
to distribute broadcast variables using efficient
algorithms. As an example, broadcast variables
can be used to give every node a copy of a
large dataset efficiently.
The other shared variables are accumulators.
These are used for counters in sums that works
well in parallel. These variables can only
be added through an associated operation.
Only the driver can read the accumulators
value, not the tasks. The tasks can only add
to it. Spark supports numeric types but programmers
can add support for new types. As an example,
you can use accumulator variables to implement
counters or sums, as in MapReduce.
Last, but not least, key-value pairs are available
in Scala, Python and Java. In Scala, you create
a key-value pair RDD by typing val pair = ('a'
, 'b'). To access each element, invoke the
._ notation. This is not zero-index, so the
._1 will return the value in the first index
and ._2 will return the value in the second
index. Java is also very similar to Scala
where it is not zero-index. You create the
Tuple2 object in Java to create a key-value
pair. In Python, it is a zero-index notation,
so the value of the first index resides in
index 0 and the second index is 1.
There are special operations available to
RDDs of key-value pairs. In an application,
you must remember to import the SparkContext
package to use PairRDDFunctions such as reduceByKey.
The most common ones are those that perform
grouping or aggregating by a key. RDDs containing
the Tuple2 object represents the key-value
pairs. Tuple2 objects are simply created by
writing (a, b) as long as you import the library
to enable Spark's implicit conversion.
If you have custom objects as the key inside
your key-value pair, remember that you will
need to provide your own equals() method to
do the comparison as well as a matching hashCode()
method.
So in the example, you have a textFile that
is just a normal RDD. Then you perform some
transformations on it and it creates a PairRDD
which allows it to invoke the reduceByKey
method that is part of the PairRDDFunctions
API.
I want to spend a little bit of time here
to explain some of the syntax that you see
on the slide. Note that in the first reduceByKey
example with the a,b => a + b. This simply
means that for the values of the same key,
add them up together. In the example on the
bottom of the slide, reduceByKey(_+_) uses
the shorthand for anonymous function taking
two parameters (a and b in our case) and adding
them together, or multiplying, or any other
operations for that matter.
Another thing I want to point is that for
the goal of brevity, all the functions are
concatenated on one line. When you actually
code it yourself, you may want split each
of the functions up. For example, do the flatMap
operation and return that to a RDD. Then from
that RDD, do the map operation to create another
RDD. Then finally, from that last RDD, invoke
the reduceByKey method. That would yield multiple
lines, but you would be able to test each
of the transformation to see if it worked
properly.
So having completed this lesson, you should
now be able to describe pretty well, RDDs.
You should also understand how to create RDDs
using various methods including from existing
datasets, external datasets such as a textFile
or from HDFS, or even just from existing RDDs.
You saw various RDD operations and saw how
to work with shared variables and key-value
pairs.
Next steps. Complete lab exercise #2 Working
with RDD operations. Then proceed to the next
lesson in this course.